Finding Aid for Women's Advocate Office (University of Michigan) records, 1970-1976
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Women's Advocate Office (University of Michigan) records 1970-1976
University of Michigan. Women's Advocate Office.
7 linear feet
87356 Bimu C550 2
Papers, 1970-1976, of the Women's Advocate of the University of Michigan, office created to meet the personal and legal needs of women at the University of Michigan. Contain reference and topical files concerning women's issues, especially abortion, childcare, health care, legal problems, affirmative action, and equal rights.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The papers were received from the Women's Advocate Office (donor no. 6122 ).
The record group is open without restriction.
The Women's Advocate Office was created to meet the personal and legal needs of women at the University of Michigan. The activities of the Women's Advocate Office have been taken over by the Commission for Women and by the Academic Women's Caucus, affiliated with the Affirmative Action Office.
A large part of the collection consists of reference files of articles related to women's issues. Topical files include materials on career planning, the Center for Continuing Education of Women, the Women's Media Center, and childcare programs and other projects for women at the university. Annual reports, evaluations and various committee reports related to the work of the Women's Advocate Office are also included.
Subjects:
Abortion.; Children--Health and hygiene--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; University of Michigan--Students.; Women--Health and hygiene--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Women--Michigan--Ann Arbor--Societies and clubs.; University of Michigan. Women's Advocate Office.; Women college students--Michigan--Ann Arbor.
- Reference File 1970-1976
  - Abortion
    - Clippings (Box 1)
    - Data, Facts (Box 1)
    - Detroit Women's Abortion Action Coalition (DWAAC) (Box 1)
    - General Historical materials (Box 1)
    - Laws (U.S.) (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous 1972 (Box 1)
    - Project of New York City Women's Liberation (Box 1)
    - Referral and Information (Box 1)
    - Reform (Box 1)
    - Repeal (Box 1)
    - Women's National Abortion Action Coalition (WONAAC) (Box 1)
  - Addresses (Box 1)
  - Admissions procedures in Psychology Ph.D. (Box 1)
  - Advocates
    - Advocate for the Disabled (Box 1)
    - Black advocate (Box 1)
    - Chicano advocate (Box 1)
    - Gay advocate (Box 1)
    - Family advocate (Box 1)
    - Native American advocate (Box 1)
    - Woman's advocate (Box 1)
    - Advocates for medical information (Box 1)
  - Alcoholics anonymous (Box 1)
  - Alternate role model program (Box 1)
  - American Council of Education (A.C.E.) (Box 1)
  - Articles
    - "Aesthetics of Childbirth" Ramparts, May 1971 (Box 1)
    - "An Answer to the Myth of Vaginal Orgasm" Fisher,Elizabeth (Box 1)
    - "Be Nicer to Secretaries, Diplomats are Advised," Gwertzman, Bernard N.Y. Times, March 6, 1972 (Box 1)
    - "Building A Movement-Free Space," Allen, Pamela (Box 1)
    - "A Challenge to Every Marriage," Shulman, Alix (Box 1)
    - "Clitoral Identity," It Ain't Me Babe, April 1972 (Box 1)
    - "Cloning, A Recycling or an Answer to Copulation?" Griffo, Michela Furies, May 1972 (Box 1)
    - "Consciousness Raising," from an unnamed leaflet (Box 1)
    - "Consciousness Raising: A Dead End?" (Box 1)
    - "Crazy Women Unite" Keever, Susan (Box 1)
    - "Employees Caution" Jeanette,Claire (Box 1)
    - "A Feminist Look at Children's Books," Feminists on Children's Literature (Box 1)
    - "Genetic Bouncing" (Box 1)
    - "Her Body,The Battleground," February 1972 (Box 1)
    - "High School Women, How to Get Along with Friends," Harris, Aneeta (Box 1)
    - "High School Women: Oppression and Liberation," Bull, Jennie (Box 1)
    - "Homosexual Marriage, Five Justifications," Baker, Jack (Box 1)
    - "How to Write Your Own Marriage Contract," Edmiston, Susan (Box 1)
    - "The Human Dignity of Women in the Church," Farians, Elizabeth (Box 1)
    - "Ideas for Consciousness Raising Groups" (Box 1)
    - "Jumping the Track," DeRivera, Alice (Box 1)
    - "Making Marriage Perfectly Clear," Gillers, Stephen, J.D. March 1972 (Box 1)
    - "Male Chauvinism" (Box 1)
    - "On Male Liberation" Sawyer, Jack (Box 1)
    - "Marriage," Cronan, Sheila (Box 1)
    - "Men Drive Women Crazy," Chesler, Phyllis (Box 1)
    - "Motherhood--Who Needs It?" Rollin, Betty Look, September 22, 1970 (Box 1)
    - "The Myth of Motherhood" (Box 1)
    - "The Myth of Vaginal Orgasm," Koedt, Anne (Box 1)
    - "Open Letter to Psychiatrists," Anthony, Nicole (Box 1)
    - "Opinionnaire on Womanhood" (Box 1)
    - "The Personal is Political," Hanisch, Carol (Box 1)
    - "Poems" (Box 1)
    - "The Preening of America," Hernandez, Arlene Star News, January 1, 1971 (Box 1)
    - "Prince Valium Meets Shrink Think," Hartman, Sylvia (Box 1)
    - "The Problem That Has No Name" (Box 1)
    - "Psychology Constructs the Female," Weisstein, Naomi (Box 1)
    - "Psychology of Professional Women," Bailyn, Lotte (Box 1)
    - "Radical Feminism, Male Responses," Koedt, Anne (Box 1)
    - "Reflections of A Male Housewife," Widmer, Kingsley (Box 1)
    - "Resistance to Consciousness Raising," Peslikis, Irene (Box 1)
    - "Rewriting Your Marriage Contract," O'Neill, George & Nena (Box 1)
    - "Saturday Morning Sexism" Kravchuki, Denise (Box 1)
    - "Sex Differences in Voting and Activism," Lansing, Marjorie (Box 1)
    - "Sexual Politics" Millet, Kate (Box 1)
    - "Songs of Women" (Box 1)
    - "The University Had Better Mind It's Own Business," Nisbet, Robert Psychology Today, March 1971 (Box 1)
    - "What Do Women Want" (Box 1)
    - "Why I Want A Wife," Syfers, Judy (Box 1)
    - "Why Women Need Less Pay (And Other Myths)," Sandler, Bernice (Box 1)
    - "Woman and Man Questionnaire," Psychology Today, February 1971 (Box 1)
    - "A Woman is 58% of Man," Levitan, Teresa; Quinn, Staines (Box 1)
    - "Woman's Lib Alive But Changing," Jacobs, Tammy (Box 1)
    - "Women and Religion" (Box 1)
    - "Women in the Russian Revolution," Dunn, Erica; Klein, Judy (Box 1)
    - "Women's Liberation-Phase IV," Tobias, Sheila (Box 1)
    - "Women, Medicine and Capitalism," Candib, Nancy (Box 1)
    - "Woman-Which Includes Man of Course" (Box 1)
  - Athletic Department (Box 1)
  - Bibliographies
    - Abortion (Box 1)
    - Annotated Bibliography, Introduction to Womens Studies (Box 1)
    - C.E.W. Research on Women Bibliography (Box 1)
    - Children's Literature (Box 1)
    - Education Today (Box 1)
    - Feminist Biology and Science (Box 1)
    - Films for Women's Studies (Box 1)
    - History of Women (Box 1)
    - High School Bibliography (Box 1)
    - Homosexual Bibliography (Box 1)
    - Indian Women (Box 1)
    - Junior High Bibliography (Box 1)
    - Pre-School Reading (Box 1)
    - Publications of the Women's Bureau (Box 1)
    - Sex Differences (Box 1)
    - Sex Role Stereotyping (Box 1)
    - Sexism (Box 1)
    - Treatment of Girls in Schools (Box 1)
    - Women (Box 1)
    - Women (Ann Arbor Public Library) (Box 1)
    - Women and the Educational Process (Box 1)
    - Women in the Near East (Box 1)
    - Women -- General (Box 1)
    - Women's Liberation (Box 1)
    - Women -- Psychology (Box 1)
  - Birth Control (Box 1)
  - Black Women's Liberation (Box 1)
  - Bus Transportation (Box 1)
  - Cable T.V. (Box 1)
  - Career Issues -- Woman (Box 1)
  - Careers (Box 1)
  - Center for Continuing Education of Women (Box 1)
  - Childbirth (Box 1)
  - College Action Committee (Box 1)
  - Commission on Women (Box 2)
    - Education Subcommittee (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
    - Office of Special Services and Programs (Cluster I) (Box 2)
    - Student Subcommittee (Box 2)
  - Committee on the Status of Women (Box 2)
  - Community High School (Box 2)
  - Conferences and Workshops (Box 2)
  - Consciousness Raising (Box 2)
  - Cooperative Extension Service (Box 2)
  - Counseling
    - General (Box 2)
    - Phone numbers (Box 2)
  - Diethylstilbestrol (DES) (Box 2)
  - Discrimination
    - Discrimination (General) (Box 2)
    - Discrimination Cases (Box 2)
    - Guidelines of Discrimination (Box 2)
    - Sex Discrimination on campus (Box 2)
    - Where to File Sex Discrimination Cases (Box 2)
  - Drugs
    - Drug Coalition (Box 2)
    - Drug Education (Box 2)
    - Drug Programs (Box 2)
  - Education and Job Opportunities for Women (Box 2)
  - Equal pay (Box 2)
  - Equal Rights Amendment (Box 2)
  - Facts on Women Workers (Box 2)
  - Famous Women
    - Davis, Angela (Box 2)
    - Douvan, Elizabeth (Box 2)
    - Goldman, Emma (Box 2)
    - Horner, Matina (Box 2)
    - Newell, Barbara (Box 2)
    - Steinem, Gloria (Box 2)
    - Tobias, Sheila (Box 2)
    - Truth, Sojourner (Box 2)
  - Feminine Figures 1971 (Box 2)
  - Feminist House (Box 2)
  - Film Collective (Box 2)
  - "Gay is Good", (leaflet (Box 2)
  - Girl Scouts (Box 2)
  - Girl's State, Ypsilanti (Box 2)
  - Graduate Women (Box 2)
  - Group Dynamics (Box 2)
  - 76 Guide (Box 2)
  - Health Collective (Box 2)
  - Health, Education and Welfare
    - Clippings (Box 2)
    - General (Box 2)
    - Report (Box 2)
  - Health Insurance (Blue Cross) (Box 2)
  - Health Service-Long Range Planning (Box 2)
  - Higher Education Resource Services (HERS) (Box 2)
  - Herself (periodical information) (Box 2)
  - History of Woman at the University (Box 2)
  - Homosexuality
    - General (Box 2)
    - Lesbians (Box 2)
  - Housing (Box 2)
  - Human Rights Department (Box 2)
  - Human Rights Party (Box 2)
  - Interviewing Skills (Box 2)
  - Job Interviewing (Box 2)
  - Journals
    - Children's Liberation (Box 2)
    - Know, Inc. (Box 2)
    - Momma (Box 2)
    - Spectre (Box 2)
    - Woman Activist (Box 2)
    - Womankind of Chicago (Box 2)
    - Woman's Information Bulletin (Box 2)
    - Women's Liberation Newsletter (Box 2)
    - Women's Liberation of Michigan Monthly (Box 2)
    - Lists of Women's Journals (Box 2)
  - Law
    - Criminal Justice (Box 2)
    - Women (Box 2)
  - League of Woman Voters (Box 2)
  - Management (Box 2)
  - Matrix (Box 2)
  - Michigan Daily (Box 2)
  - Michigan Union (Box 2)
  - Michigan Women in Science (Box 2)
  - National Women's Political Caucus (Box 2)
  - Network for Economic Rights (Box 2)
  - New Understanding of Justice (Box 2)
  - National Organization For Women
    - National (Box 2)
    - Local (Box 2)
  - Ordering (Box 2)
  - Office of Special Services and Programs (OSSP)
    - General (Box 2)
    - Advocates (Box 2)
      (see also Advocates)
    - Correspondence (Box 2)
    - Meetings (Box 2)
    - Other Advocates and Programs (Box 2)
    - Finances (Box 3)
      - Budgets 1972/1973 1973-1974 (Box 3)
      - Budget Proposals and priorities (Box 3)
      - Funding (Box 3)
    - Committees
      - Administrative Committee (Box 3)
      - Communications Subcommittee (Box 3)
      - Unit Committee (Box 3)
      - Office of Student Organizations (Box 3)
      - Ombudsperson (Box 3)
      - Office of Student Services (Box 3)
      - Other offices (Box 3)
      - Proposals (Box 3)
      - Publications (list) (Box 3)
      - Rooms (Box 3)
      - Secretary constituency services (Box 3)
  - Probe
    - Complaint (Box 3)
    - General (Box 3)
    - Organizations (Box 3)
    - Publications (Box 3)
  - Problem Pregnancy Task Force (Box 3)
  - Public Schools (Box 3)
  - Radical Lesbians (Box 3)
  - Sesame Street (Box 3)
  - Sex Related Medical Services (Box 3)
  - Skills-Crafts Services Directory (Box 3)
  - Social Security (Box 3)
  - Staff Benefits (Box 3)
  - Student Government Council (Box 3)
  - Student Health Insurance (Box 3)
  - Teach-in On Women (Box 3)
  - Tuition Refund Request (Box 3)
  - United Women's Contingent (Box 3)
  - University Record (Box 3)
  - Volunteer Action Committee (Box 3)
  - Voting Petitions (Box 3)
  - Women from Other Cultures
    - American Indian Women (Box 3)
    - Chinese Women (Box 3)
    - Vietnamese Women (Box 3)
  - Women in Business (Box 3)
  - Women in the School of Education (Box 3)
  - Women's Advocate
    - Memos to Administration (Box 3)
    - Activities (Box 3)
    - Salary study (Box 3)
  - Women's Center (Box 3)
  - Women's Coalition (Box 3)
  - Women's Community School (Box 3)
  - Women's Crisis Center (Box 3)
  - Women's Liberation of Michigan (Box 3)
  - Women's Movement -- Clippings (Box 3)
  - Women's Political Caucus (Box 3)
  - Women's Rights Address Books (Box 3)
  - Women's Studies
    - Courses and Lectures (Box 3)
    - General (Box 3)
    - Proposals for Women's Studies (Box 3)
  - Women Who Work (Box 3)
  - Women Uniting to End the War (Box 3)
- Topical File
  - Abortion (Box 3)
  - Black Women (Box 3)
  - Clericals (Box 3)
  - Conferences
    - New Research on Women II (Box 3)
    - Conferences on Women (Box 3)
    - Conferences -- Historical (Box 3)
  - Famous Women
    - Bella Abzug (Box 3)
    - Judith Bardwick (Box 3)
    - Shirley Chisolm (Box 3)
    - Angela Davis (Box 3)
    - Clippings -- People (Box 3)
    - Famous Sisters Checklist (Box 3)
    - Gloria Steinem (Box 3)
  - Feminist Research Project (Box 3)
  - Foreign Women (Box 3)
  - Funding
    - Ann Arbor Foundations (Box 4)
    - Fund Raising (Box 4)
    - Requests for Funding (Box 4)
    - Steinem-Sloan Planning Committee (Box 4)
  - Gay Liberation
    - Gay Advocates-Student Service (Box 4)
    - Gay Community (Box 4)
    - Gay Women-Articles and clippings (Box 4)
  - Guild House (Box 4)
  - Health Care for Women
    - Birth Control (Box 4)
    - Childbirth (Box 4)
    - Diethylstilbestrol (Box 4)
    - Facilities/Services Health Planning (Box 4)
    - Midwives (Box 4)
    - Self-help (Box 4)
    - Women's Community Clinic (Box 4)
    - Women and Medicare (Box 4)
  - Housing (Box 4)
  - International Women's Year, 8 folders (Box 4)
  - Legal
    - Ann Arbor Human Rights Ordinance (Box 4)
    - Child Care Legislation and Tax Deductions (Box 4)
    - Criminal Justice-Interested Organizations (Box 4)
    - Title IX, 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Equal Employment Opportunity Act -- 1972 (Box 4)
    - Equal Rights Amendment, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Filing Sex Discrimination suits (Box 4)
    - Michigan Legislation (Box 4)
    - Michigan Districts (map) (Box 4)
    - Minnesota Legislation (Box 4)
    - Minors (Box 4)
    - Pregnant High School Women (Box 4)
    - Sex Discrimination in Higher Education (Box 4)
    - Women: Law and Government (Box 4)
    - Women Legislative Caucus (Box 4)
  - Marriage
    - Divorce (Box 4)
    - Name Change (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - Media
    - Ann Arbor Women's Film Festival (Box 4)
    - Audio-Visual Center -- UM (Box 4)
    - Book Review "Clean Sweep" (Box 4)
    - Cable Television (Box 4)
    - Center for the Continuing Education of Women (Box 4)
    - Comics (Box 4)
    - Films (Box 4)
    - Films: Women's Studies (Box 4)
    - Graphics (Box 4)
    - Local Newspapers (Box 4)
    - Local T.V. and Radio Stations (Box 4)
    - Mad Madonnas (Box 4)
    - Media Group (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 4)
    - Music: Sung (Box 4)
    - Plays and Theatre (Box 4)
    - Radio (Box 4)
    - Slide Show: Role Reversal (Box 4)
    - Talent: Feminist (Box 4)
    - Tapes (Box 4)
    - Women's Film Collective (Box 4)
    - Women in Media (Box 4)
    - Women's Media Center (Box 4)
  - Opportunity Award (Box 5)
  - Planned Parenthood 1976 (Box 5)
  - Prisons
    - Committee for New Understanding of Justice (Box 5)
    - Detroit House of Correction (Box 5)
  - Programming
    - Film Festival (Box 5)
    - Lesbian Counselors (Box 5)
    - Michigan Scholars Conference 1975 (Box 5)
    - M.B.O. (Box 5)
    - Program Planning (Box 5)
    - School of Education, Commission for Women (Box 5)
    - Student Government Council Programs (Box 5)
    - Summer Orientation (Box 5)
    - Values and Decision-Making Seminar (Box 5)
  - Publications
    - Adult Continuing Education: Reporter (Box 5)
    - Feminist Press (Box 5)
    - Information Service: University of Michigan (Box 5)
    - Lists of Sources and Outlets (Box 5)
    - Newsletter and Clearinghouse Women's Studies\ (Box 5)
    - People Yellow Pages (Box 5)
    - Research Administration-Reporter (Box 5)
    - Research News (Box 5)
    - University Management Intercom (Box 5)
    - University Publication Housing (Box 5)
    - Women's Poetry (Box 5)
    - Women's Information Network: Bulletins and calendars (Box 5)
    - Women's Studies Newsletter (Box 5)
  - Publicity
    - Local Newspaper (Box 5)
    - Local Printers (Box 5)
  - Questionnaires (Box 5)
  - Security on Campus (Box 5)
  - Speeches (Box 5)
  - Statistical Facts (Box 5)
  - Rape
    - General (Box 5)
    - Anti-rape letters (Box 5)
  - Religion and Women (Box 5)
  - Summer Orientation
    - General (Box 5)
    - Fall Evaluations (Box 5)
    - Group 1-2 Evaluation (Box 5)
    - Group 3-5 Evaluation (Box 5)
    - Group 6 Evaluation (Box 5)
  - University of Michigan
    - Alumni Association (Box 5)
    - Career Planning and Placement (Box 5)
    - Counseling (Box 5)
    - Classification Description (Box 5)
    - Faculty Women (Box 5)
    - Health Service (Box 5)
    - L.S.A. Dean's Office (Box 5)
    - Scholarship (Box 5)
    - Standard Practice Guide: U-M (Box 5)
    - Summer Orientation (Box 5)
    - Unions -- General (Box 5)
    - University Office -- Placement (Box 5)
  - Welfare (Box 5)
  - Women's Advocate Office
    - Annual Reports 1972-1974, 3 folders (Box 5)
    - Articles (Box 5)
    - Associate Position-Job Description (Box 5)
    - Budget Proposals 1972-1974, 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Evaluation (Box 6)
    - First Objectives (Box 6)
    - Monthly Report (Box 6)
    - Program and Budget (Box 6)
    - Program Evaluation 1971-1973, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Program Log 1975-1976 (Box 6)
    - Program Projections 1973-1974 (Box 6)
    - Women's Advocate Job Description (Box 6)
  - Workshop
    - Non-academic Job Hunting (Box 6)
    - Response and Associates, "Preparing Women to Manage a Changing Society" (Box 6)
    - "Women's Assembly" (Box 6)
    - "Women's Programs at U.M. Dearborn" (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 6)
- Child Care
  - Amalgamated Child Day Care and Health Center (Box 6)
  - Articles on Day Care (Box 6)
  - Associations (Box 6)
  - Budgets (Box 6)
  - Center for Early Childhood Development (Box 6)
  - Centrum (Box 6)
  - Child Care Action Center (Box 6)
  - Child Care Coalition (Box 6)
  - Child Care Commitment Document (Box 6)
  - Child Care Development and Progress (Box 6)
  - Child Care Services Information (Box 6)
  - Child Care Task Force (Box 6)
  - Child Care Task Force Minutes (Box 6)
  - Child Care Telephone Survey (Box 6)
  - Clippings Child Care (Box 6)
  - Community Coordinate Child Care (Box 6)
  - Community Day Care (Box 6)
  - Continuing Education for Women (Box 6)
  - Correspondence/Child Care (Box 6)
  - Curtis, Carla (Box 6)
  - Day Care in Metropolitan Detroit (Box 6)
  - Demonstrations (Box 6)
  - Discretionary (Box 6)
  - Education: Techniques and Theory (Box 6)
  - Facilities (Box 6)
  - Fleming, Mrs. Robben (Box 6)
  - Grants (Box 6)
  - Groups (Box 6)
  - Law School Child Care (Box 6)
  - Legal Guidelines (Box 6)
  - Linguistics: Child Care (Box 6)
  - Madelon Pound Center:
    - Applications (Box 6)
    - Board of Advisor (Box 6)
    - Correspondence (Box 6)
    - Proposal (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 6)
  - North Campus Child Care Committee (Box 6)
  - Office of Child Development (Box 6)
  - Progress Reports (Box 7)
  - Project Community (Box 7)
  - Proposal for University Involvement in Child Care (Box 7)
  - Publications (Box 7)
  - Report: Alternatives for University Involvement in Child Care (Box 7)
  - Report: University of Michigan position paper (Box 7)
  - Request for continuation of Child Care Advocate Position (Box 7)
  - Request for Information School of Architecture (Box 7)
  - Selection of Child Care Advocate Setting up a Day Care Center (Box 7)
  - Social Security Title IV A Fund (Box 7)
  - Student Government Council and Child Care Surveys (Box 7)
  - University of Pittsburgh: Proposal for Day Care Project (Box 7)
  - Washtenaw County Community Coordinated Child Care Newsletter (Box 7)
  - Washtenaw County Department of Social Services/Child Care (Box 7)
- Papers
  - 1970-1976, 10 folders (Box 7)
- Reports
  - Annual Report,1974-1975Student Organizational Services (Box 7)
  - Commission to Study Student Governance (Box 7)
  - Committee to Study Advocacy at the University of Michigan (Box 7)
  - Neighborhood Facilities Space Utilization Report, City of Ann Arbor (Box 7)
  - Orientation to Culture in the U.S.A., International Center of the University of Michigan (Box 7)
  - William Munroe Trotter House, Budgetary Request 1973-1974 (Box 7)
  - Association of American Colleges, The Project on the Status and Education of Women (Box 7)